Hey, what's going on guys? In this tutorial,
we are gonna go through and begin assembling our clips into
our timeline. Uh, at this point,
you have already modularized your clips so you know what shots are
valuable, which ones you want to take, which ones you want to use, actually. Um,
so let's just jump into Premier and begin this process. So over here in Premier,
I actually just open up a brand new, uh, sequence, I'm sorry, uh,
a brand new project. And over here you can see my bins over here. Um,
and I still haven't yet put in my modular clips yet,
and I'm about to do that now. But, uh, for the sake of this tutorial,
I actually recorded a voiceover, and so I'm going to, uh,
include that in there as well. But, um,
let me just go back really quick because I,
this is actually a client project and I have a script written for it,
which is over here.
And so I wanted to just kind of quickly go over this with you.
It's not gonna be exact, but what I'm trying to relate to you is,
um, the structure. Okay? So how we script everything, uh,
is very much that similar format, the ADA format.
So you have the scroll stopper, the hook, the introduction, um, in this case,
uh, case study and proof authority. And then we have, um,
how it works and, and then the C t A. All right?
So we are gonna go through this process. Um, with the clips.
This ad can turn out, I, I don't even know,
I'm just gonna edit this and see how it goes. But along the way, we will, um,
you know, we'll, we'll figure it out. But, uh,
let's go back into our premier and let's start working with some of this
footage. All right, so, uh, going into the modular raws,
you can see that everything here is already pre-labeled.
Um, and the sound is actually removed as well,
because I don't need the sound. So that's actually one less, one less layer.
So you can see here we've got browsing mobile phone craving
for junk foods. Okay, so real quick,
the product is actually a weight loss product. So when we shot this,
we wanted to get a ton of different hooks and scroll stoppers, um,
that could potentially grab attention. And so, you know,
we got a bunch of junk food and did all this crazy stuff. And, um, you know,
this is definitely gonna grab attention, uh, later on. So,
but we also shot, you know,
shots like this where the product's being put out into the hand. Uh,
lots of lots of cool dynamic things,
but I'm pretty sure we can make a really effective video ad with the examples at
hand. So let's, let's do it. Alright,
so I'm gonna take all my raws here, highlight all of them,
and I'm just gonna drag them into my, my raw bin. Fantastic.
Uh, I have a few other assets here, like my voiceover,
which I'll put there into music, or I'll actually put in sound effects.
And I have a couple other clips in here that I didn't modularize yet,
but pharmacy and receiving package. So I'll put that into my raws. Great.
Okay, so first step, uh, is creating a sequence, right?
So I'll go into my sequence bin, right click new item sequence.
And if you guys haven't done this already,
we have some free training on how to create presets. Um,
so I definitely recommend doing that. So for this example,
I'm gonna go with nine by 16. It's a very hot, um,
I would say vertical placement nowadays. TikTok, you know, reels, all of that.
So we'll, we'll do nine by 16. I'm just gonna call this nine by 16, um,
top of funnel. Alright, boom. We're good to go.
So first, first things first, right?
We want to kind of work in a logical order. So, um,
we're talking about the scroll stopper here,
and we want to just start to lay down what that scroll stopper potential could
be. And in this case, uh, it's just kind of vague. So, um,
strong visual audio and headline. Uh, you know,
just by going through the clips, I think we saw some great potential here.
So I'm actually gonna change the view so that I can actually see these shots a
little bit more clearly.
'cause I like to do the thumbnail view because that way I know what I'm looking
at. Um, but let's just call,
let's just do like this example's kind of fun. Yeah,
that's a nice, that's a cool, cool shot. So, um, what I like to do,
instead of dragging, you know, this over like that,
I actually double click the shot and then click on this little, um,
icon right here. And what it does is it just drags the video over like that,
all right? I, I,
I really like that 'cause it's one less layer that I have to worry about, um,
when it comes to like, setting things up. So boom, I have this shot,
but remember we only wanna do three seconds or so, right?
So that's three second mark right there. One thing that I like to do,
um, in terms of, you know,
keeping things within a a a time segment, you can obviously, you can add,
let's say like a chapter queue right here at the three second mark.
Or you could do a marker,
something like that where it shows you three seconds is right there. Um,
another thing that I could do, you know, if you don't have it, it it,
because one, one thing is that this thing stays still. Um, so for example,
if I were to go over here and I wanted three seconds here,
it'd be more difficult to count.
So I will go in here and then create a,
what's it called? A, uh, an adjustment layer, just,
just regular adjustment layer.
And I'll drag it onto my timeline like that,
and then I will actually shorten it.
So I know that this is a three second segment right here. So wherever I go,
this is kind of my placeholder, so I know, okay,
this is three seconds right there. Cool. So with that being said,
I like to sometimes add a little bit of space in between here. Um,
just a little bit of room before doing any hooks, just so to be honest, I like,
uh, 'cause it can vary and I'll show you later on why,
why we do something like that. But,
so in this shot we have him putting it in his eyes
and we're, we're just trying to find like, what's the best shot right here.
Oh yeah, I think, you know, he's not really doing much here, but when he,
when he picks it up, I feel like is really compelling. So I'm just gonna,
I'm just gonna delete that. I, I hit,
I hit see and now I'm just gonna delete that and I'm gonna drag it over here.
Um, and I'm gonna review this, so I'm hitting plus to zoom in.
Let's review it one more time. Okay, fantastic.
So we have this three seconds and the clip is longer.
What I like to do is actually speed up the clip.
So if I have all this extra space, obviously we don't need all of it,
right? So I just want to get that and then get his eyeballs, like,
yeah, like right there. So I'm gonna cut that. All right,
delete. And what I'm gonna do is hit the, the rate tool,
which is this shortcut right here, the rate stretch tool.
And I'm just gonna bring it down like that so I can match exactly that three
second window. Cool.
So boom, now I have my first hook. All right?
So if I wanted to go back and actually add a second hook,
this is what I would normally do. So because I have these all modularized,
it makes my life so much easier, right?
So I have this shot and then from here, um,
and I'm not actually gonna like cut the whole thing in there 'cause I don't,
I don't think I need to, it's kind of repetitive.
So I'll just bring it in and then end it there.
And I'll hit the out the o for out,
click the drag video in.
And what I'm actually gonna do is I'm gonna move this adjustment layer up top
just so I have a little bit of space here.
But when you're doing hooks,
you actually wanna just stack 'em on top of each other, okay?
Because this is going to, this is gonna allow you to, um,
select the hook variation that you want to eventually export. Um,
so what you can do by toggling in between them is hit command shift e
like this.
And you'll be able to not delete it and not hide it. So this,
this little feature will hide the entire track,
but when you do com command or control shift e it actually just hides it
for a temporary bit of time or however long you know,
you decide to keep it hidden. So
for the example's sake, let's just keep it like that.
And I'm happy with this shot right here. I think it looks really cool and weird.
So now let's start working through our actual,
uh, story like our, our script, right?
This medically customized metabolic weight loss program by new images helping
thousands. Okay, cool. So the shot is saying show closeup of packaging,
or any before and afters available. So we definitely have, uh,
closeups of the packaging. So let's throw that in there. All right,
so what do we got over here? We've got this shot. Let's get a clear one.
And it's not bad. Yeah, this one's cool.
Let's check this one.
I,
By the way, there's no sound on this, so it's, uh,
so let's go with something just like more straightforward like this.
I kinda like that. And yeah, we'll, we'll take that whole clip.
Plug it in. All right. So boom,
This medical da, da, da has been da, da da, da da. All right.
And so what I'll do is try to just keep this like, so as we know,
this is three seconds, right?
So let's try to keep this thing three seconds as well. I'll do the rate tool,
bring that down, speed it up so we have room for captions.
Okay, good. Next we've got, um, okay,
so closeup of packaging, it's called wait list, show, product package.
And I know we have some product package shots here,
but we wanna make it a little bit more different than that last shot, right? So
yeah, we can do something like this.
See if I got any other photo.
Yeah, I think this will be a good shot because there's a lot of, um,
a lot of space around it and we can, um,
use that space for captions. So
1, 2, 3. Cool, happy with that.
'cause we're gonna be using these as captions in, in a recent study. Da,
da da da da da. Patient's lost. Okay? So, um,
I'm not gonna put all this information in there. Instead I'm just gonna have a,
a shot of an actress like posing.
So it looks like they lost weight.
So this one, this is obviously a pain point, but we can have,
yeah, we can do something like this where he's like flexing, right?
It's not bad of a shot, but I feel like women sell better. So,
okay, a little cheesy there, but let's do something like this, okay? In
out cool. Boom.
And then this is gonna be a little bit of a longer shot because I know there's a
lot of description in the text, so, great. Okay.
Wait list is a description only, da, da, da treatment plan developed by,
so closeup of the product. Let's do another closeup of the product.
Okay? Just plug that in. Okay.
Clearly this is a really long shot and you gotta remember, we want quick cuts.
We don't want a ton of information here at a time. So, uh, as you can see,
this one's okay, depending on the captions. Three seconds.
Probably trim this down too.
Yeah, I think I, I just like her, like
we might even do, it might even be worth to add, uh,
a second one in here so that it looks a little bit more
So we can add more people in the shot.
Okay, Good.
And I'm just gonna cut that right now. I'm just kind of, kind of playing,
playing it by ear because once we get the, uh, the titles in,
we'll kind of get a feel for it. So we're already at 14 seconds. All right,
so that's, that's kind of long. Well actually,
that's trim this all the way down.
So if you wanted to trim all this space right here,
a quick shortcut is w it'll just push everything down.
So boom title, good.
I honestly feel like it's a little long.
I think that's probably where I would cut right there. 'cause it's like,
so what I mean by adding little space right here is now I know
like this one would start here instead. So
boom,
good ingredients come up.
Case studies. I feel like he should already be flexing
right here. Cool.
I mean, there's, there's options here.
You could do a split screen or you could do both of them one after another
and it isn't available at your local pharmacy. All right,
so I know that we have pharmacy shots.
I
In here, so pharmacy,
all right, this is actually me going into the pharmacy. So,
all right, so these aren't modularized. So,
um,
one thing that you need to do with U G C shots is you're gonna right click or
you're gonna select them all right click, go to modify, interpret footage,
and then you want to change the color space override, um,
because it comes out a little like dull like this, I don't know,
it's with the new iPhones, but change it to 2020 scene.
And your, your videos are gonna look like tremendously different.
So let's,
so I know I did a little like whipp pen there,
so it's a little bit of a visuals.
Boom. Okay, so clearly this one's way bigger, right?
Because they didn't modularize it. So, uh,
shortcut to getting to your effects control panel is shift f uh,
shift five here. I'm just gonna scale this bad boy down like this.
Uh, another shortcut you can do to scale down. If you click on motion, you can,
uh, get the little bounding box and then adjust it that way. That's,
that's really nice and helpful. So, boom,
not available to any store pharmacy. So I'm just gonna cut this,
I don't need that. All right,
let's go back to the script, See if waitlist is for you.
Visit NewAge medical screen Recording. Alright, so, uh,
I don't have a screen recording, but I do have him over the shoulder, uh,
basically doing the same thing. So I'm gonna get that shot.
I remember that was earlier on right here. Cool.
So let's go here. Yeah, we don't need that whole process,
so let's just get that up to when he selects a package.
So o drag it in. And that's a really long clip,
so we're gonna speed that up. And I feel like this drags a little bit,
so let's speed that up as well.
We will see when the captains come in. Boom.
Okay, so there's a little bit of dead space here. I'm gonna trim that.
I'm gonna get it right when he starts actually moving his finger.
Cool. All right, so I'm gonna, I'm gonna speed this thing up,
maybe 150. Um, so if you don't wanna use the rate tool,
uh, I would suggest just right clicking and then going to speed duration,
and then hitting one 50. And then just go in increments of like one 50 or, uh,
increments of 50 or a hundred. So it's like 1.5 or two x speed.
This goes for like reducing the speed as well.
Yeah, so I would probably test out just to see if it,
if it moves a little faster. Yeah, that's better.
Boom. Cool. I would prob I would just cut there. Cut, delete.
And so next we've got screen recording. Begin your transformation today.
All right,
so we've got maybe like one additional
we can do, like a product shot if they, if we have one.
Okay, let's see what we got here. Begin your transformation today. So, you know,
with, with begin your transformation today, um, we definitely like,
it'd be nice to have some sort of person.
Yeah, here we go. It's a nice little ending. Beginner your transformation today.
He's flexing. All right, that could be a nice little ending there.
And I'll cut there 'cause he's not really doing anything
cool. And I think the rest of the video could just have the, uh, like an outro,
uh, with the logo and c t a. So
Pretty much from here, let's just go back to our steps, right? So we,
we pretty much put all of the, uh, the shots together, okay?
So this is if you're following a script and you already know what,
what clips you have. So real quick,
going back to the steps here, modularizing clips,
now we assemble timeline and adds some music. Um,
it really comes down now if we want to add music, we can add music later,
to be honest, because the timing is gonna be, it's gonna affect everything.
So I would say this is pretty, pretty solid for, uh, initial cut.
And next we're gonna add titles, overlays and effects.
So let's play this through one, one time no sound.
Honestly, it's sometimes better to play to edit videos, excuse me,
to edit videos without sound because you actually can feel the pacing more,
um, unless the, the music, you know, unless you are cutting to music,
like cutting to the beat. And in this scenario,
like this case like weight loss stuff, like,
you're not gonna be really cutting to the beat.
Like people aren't really interested in that. You know,
when you cut to the beat, it's something that's hip, that's cool, you know,
there's a excitement to it. In this case, we're just, it's very informational,
cut and dry. But what we wanna do is just kind of feel where the video is,
where's it, where's it lagging? Where, where,
where do we need to spice the spice something up. So boom.
Okay,
So that will have like the, the product little things there. Good.
Okay, I feel like that one is a little long. So let's actually, um,
and you can tell obviously the,
the clip itself is long and I don't think it needs to be that long.
So let's speed this up to let's try 300 and see, we,
we've we've shaved almost an entire second. That's big.
It's big when it comes to ads.
Cool. Yeah, I think that, I think that's a solid, solid story.
So again, we've got hook, we've got, um,
interest, all right, we're, we've got desire. This is probably where we,
we might be able to improve on the video. Um,
so we got interest right here. This could be interesting.
I feel like it could be missing something, um,
in terms of like keeping them engaged because it's going straight into the
product. I feel like there's,
there could be something here that can spice it up. Okay,
here we go. This might be a better shot. Yeah,
there's just a little bit more entertainment value here, you know, shaking it.
There's more visuals going on. So I'm gonna use that clip.
I'm actually gonna insert it here. And if you hold commander control, um,
you can actually insert it just like that in between your shots.
So what I'm gonna do is,
Yeah, see there's a little bit more of like a,
just like a visual stimulation going on here that you're like, what was that?
Right? So you go from this, you're, you've,
you've got your attention now I want to keep your interest. Okay, what is that?
So I'll add some effects to this later on, and I think it'll,
it'll maintain your attention. But for now,
I think this is pretty solid. Um, lemme just review this clip really quick,
see what we've got going on. Okay, she's just working.
There's another shot of, of shaking the green bottle. Okay? So
we've got a lot of crazy, crazy hooks here. Ice cream on pizza.
All right, let's watch this one more time. That looks fun. All right,
this new product, da da da. I would add a zoom in here and, uh,
the titles pop up. Add the little boom, boom, boom.
I like that. Da da da da, da. Solid, solid,
solid and cool. All right, I'm actually really happy with that.
I'm gonna save it.
And next we're gonna go over the titles and effects and all that fun stuff.
All right, thanks for watching me and I hope you are following along.
So see you in the next one.